Finding aid to the Elizabeth McGrew Kimball Papers CA.MS.00158
Smith College Archives
Elizabeth McGrew Kimball Papers
1900-1973
Smith College Archives
Kimball, Elizabeth McGrew
CA.MS.00158
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
This collection includes correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings and publications relating to Elizabeth McGrew Kimball's career at Smith College and elsewhere.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth McGrew Kimball was born in Bareilly, India, where her mother worked as a doctor and her father as a missionary. She came to the United States at the age of five and was home-schooled by tutors and governesses until age 11. When she was 13, Kimball was taken out of school because of poor health and went to live with her grandmother. Kimball went on to graduate from Smith College in 1901. She continued living in Northampton with her husband, Everett Kimball, who joined the Smith faculty in 1904. She was involved in many of Smith College's affairs, most predominantly with the Alumnae Association. She was also the only museum assistant to be employed by the college, an accomplishment that made her family quite proud. Kimball traveled all over the world during her lifetime, to places such as France, Italy, England, Egypt, Palestine, Lebanon and Syria. She was an avid collector of scarves and owned pieces from all parts of the globe that dated as far back as the seventeenth century. Kimball was given the opportunity to study art in Paris with Andre Lhote, and created many works during her adult life, including watercolors, oils, pastels and drawings. She was also employed by the U. S. State Department for three and a half years, working closely with a Geological Survey. Her advanced knowledge of French, German, Italian and English made her overqualified for the job. She continued working after her husband retired from Smith in 1946 for the State Department, as part of a Water Conservation Tour in western Massachusetts. Kimball passed away at the age of 94 on January 9, 1973 in Los Angeles, California, where she had lived with her son and daughter-in-law.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings and publications relating to Kimball's career at Smith College and elsewhere.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials in the Elizabeth McGrew Kimball papers came to the College Archives from a number of sources.
Kimball, Elizabeth McGrew
- Alumnae Fund, undated (Box 889, Folder 1)
- Correspondence-Duryee, Alice, 1900-1901 (Box 889, Folder 2)
- Correspondence-Duryee, Alice, 1902 (Box 889, Folder 3)
- Correspondence-Duryee, Alice, 1903 (Box 889, Folder 4)
- Correspondence-Duryee, Alice, 1904 (Box 889, Folder 5)
- Correspondence-Duryee, Alice, 1905 (Box 889, Folder 6)
- Correspondence-Duryee, Alice, 1906-1916 (Box 889, Folder 7)
- Correspondence-Lapham, Helen A., 1959-1961 (Box 889, Folder 8)
- Correspondence-Strong, Beulah, 1936-1938 (Box 889, Folder 9)
- Photographs, 1964-1973 (Box 889, Folder 10)
- Water Conservation Tour, 1957-1959 (Box 889, Folder 11)
- Water Conservation Tour-Brochures, 1953-1958 (Box 889, Folder 12)
- Zoology Laboratory Book, 1901 (Box 889, Folder 13)